<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Austri</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="https://dreamrealmstorytellers.com/svilland/">Dream Realm Storytellers</author>
		<update version="0.0.2">
			<file name="race-austri.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ShadowLinks/svilland-elements/main/svilland/race-austri.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<element name="Austri" type="Race" source="Svilland" id="ID_RACE_AUSTRI">
		<description>
			<p class="flavor">Proud Austris mostly live in Green Lights of the East. Behind the walls of the capital city Thorath, they built a civilization, the likes of which was never before seen in Svilland. Here, armies in green cloaks wander in the wild to protect the people of the kingdom. They are a proud folk; proud of their Gods and Goddesses, lives, and kingdom.</p>
			<h4>LONG LIVE THE KINGDOM</h4>
			<p class="indent">compared to other regions. People’s struggles are not with nature, but with other people. In this region, you can easily buy the pelt of a wild animal instead of hunting it, but bargaining can be just as hard as hunting. Bureaucracy keeps things in order in the cities of the region, but it also slows things down.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once called the Kingdom of Eastern Horn, Green Lights of the East has always been in war with the people who opposed them. Their crusade in the name of Odin, Tyr, and Thor is still going strong.</p>
			<h4>RELATIONS</h4>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Dvergr:</strong> “Good blacksmiths, but a strange folk. They are from another realm, so they should let us keep this one for ourselves.”</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Half-Jotunn:</strong> “They make good honey and good mead, but we should still be careful when approaching one; some are still loyal to Odd.”</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Mithal:</strong> “Once a great and honorable enemy, now a broken kind. With the Bear King dead and the civil war of the uncle and the niece, the Mithals are divided, but one must never underestimate them. They still have the potential to rise from their ashes.”</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Kuning:</strong> “They once lived in peace with our people, but then they suffered atrocities they did not deserve. They should dust themselves off and rise again.”</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Vestri:</strong> “Ignorant seamen. They think they are invincible with their naval forces but when our forces strike like a green lightning, all will fall. Their time will come… but for now, let them keep fishing.”</p>
			<h4>AUSTRI NAMES</h4>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Male Names:</strong> Asmund, Bergvid, Eiwald, Grimwald, Hamund, Iarl, Jarlebanke, Kolbein, Modolf, Odinqar, Othraq, Ragi, Thorwald, Ulfjolt, Varsvir</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Female Names:</strong> Astrid, Bergljot, Dalla, Frijda, Gyda, Katla, Luta, Mina, Oline, Rita, Sigrun Tanja, Ygritte, Yrsa</p>
			<h4>AUSTRI TRAITS</h4>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Ability Score Increase </strong> Your Charisma score increases by 2 and your Intelligence score increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Age </strong> Austri live nearly 70-90 years and they become adults when they are 19.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Alignment </strong> Because of the rules and bureaucracy in the Kingdom, the Austri tend to be lawful.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Size </strong> The Austri average is in between 5-7 feet and 125-250 pounds and medium size. </p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Speed </strong> Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Languages </strong> Austris (Common).</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Quick Thinking </strong> You have a +1 bonus on initiative rolls.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Kingdom’s Arsenal</strong> Due to conscription you are proficient with longsword, saex, svillander sling, or warhammer.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Civilised</strong> You know how things work in a civilized society. You can choose to have advantage on a Charisma check. When you use this feature twice, you need to take a short or long rest to use it again.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="names" type="male">Asmund, Bergvid, Eiwald, Grimwald, Hamund, Iarl, Jarlebanke, Kolbein, Modolf, Odinqar, Othraq, Ragi, Thorwald, Ulfjolt, Varsvir</set>
			<set name="names" type="female">Astrid, Bergljot, Dalla, Frijda, Gyda, Katla, Luta, Mina, Oline, Rita, Sigrun Tanja, Ygritte, Yrsa</set>
			<set name="names format">{{name}}</set>
			<set name="height" modifier="2d8">6'0"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="2d6">180 lb.</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="charisma" value="2" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
			<stat name="intelligence" value="1" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Custom Ability Score Improvement +2 (Austri)" supports="Custom Ability Score Increase 2" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Custom Ability Score Improvement +1 (Austri)" supports="Custom Ability Score Increase 1" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />
			<select type="Language" name="Customized Language" supports="Custom Race Language" number="1"  requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="Quick Thinking" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="Kingdom’s Arsenal"/>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="Civilised"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Quick Thinking" type="Racial Trait" source="Svilland" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_QUICK_THINKING">
		<description>
			<p>You have a +1 bonus on initiative rolls.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have a +1 bonus on initiative rolls.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="initiative" value="1"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Kingdom’s Arsenal" type="Racial Trait" source="Svilland" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KINGDOMS_ARSENAL">
		<description>
			<p>Due to conscription you are proficient with shortsword, longsword or warhammer.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Due to the conscription, you are proficient with the longsword, saex, svillander sling, and warhammer.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SAEX" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SVILLANDER_SLING" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGSWORD" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_WARHAMMER" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Simple/Martial Weapon or Tool, Kingdom’s Arsenal" number="2" supports="Weapon||Tool" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Civilised" type="Racial Trait" source="Svilland" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_CIVILISED">
		<description>
			<p>You know how things work in a civilized society. You can choose to have advantage on a Charisma check. When you use this feature twice, you need to take a short or long rest to use it again.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
			<description> You can choose to have advantage on a Charisma check. When you use this feature twice, you need to take a short or long rest to use it again.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>