<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Austri</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="https://dreamrealmstorytellers.com/svilland/">Dream Realm Storytellers</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="race-austri.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/The-Multitud-e/svilland-elements/main/svilland/race-austri.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<element name="Austri" type="Race" source="Svilland" id="ID_RACE_AUSTRI">
		<description>
			<p class="flavor">Proud Austri mostly live in the Green Light of the East. Behind the walls of the capital city Thorath, they are building a civilization, the likes of which no one ever saw in Svilland. Armies in green cloaks, wander in the wild to protect the people of the kingdom. They are the most honorable humans in the Nordic lands, if you ask them. Their hair is generally blonde, and they are generally pale.</p>
			<h4>LONG LIVE THE KINGDOM</h4>
			<p class="indent">Life in the Green Light of the East has different hardships, compared to other regions. People generally don’t struggle with nature, but with other people. In this region, instead of hunting a wild animal you can easily buy its pelt, but bargaining can be just hard as hunting in the Kingdom. Bureaucracy keeps things in order in the cities of the region, but it also slows things down. Once named Kingdom of Eastern Horn, Green Light of the East Kingdom has always been in war with the people who opposed them. Their crusade in the name of Odin, Tyr and Thor is still going strong.</p>
			<h4>RELATIONS</h4>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Dvergr:</strong> “Good blacksmiths but not a trustworthy folk. They are from another land, so they should let us keep this one for ourselves.”</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Half-Jotunn:</strong> “Bunch of uncivilized monsters. The Half-Jotnar are not welcome in our empire. Their savagery cannot be overlooked.”</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Mithal:</strong> “Once a great and honorable enemy, now a broken kind. With the Bear King dead, the Mithal are divided, but one must never underestimate them. They have a potential to rise up.”</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Kuning:</strong> “They once lived in peace with our people, now they wander Svilland aimlessly. They denounced our Gods, so they had it coming.”</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Vestri:</strong> “Ignorant seamen. They think they are invincible with their naval forces but when our forces strike like a green lightning, all will fall. Their time will come… but for now, let them keep fishing.”</p>
			<h4>AUSTRI NAMES</h4>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Male Names:</strong> Asmund, Bergvid, Eiwald, Grimwald, Hamund, Iarl, Jarlebanke, Kolbein, Modolf, Odinqar, Othraq, Ragi, Thorwald, Ulfjolt, Varsvir</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Female Names:</strong> Astrid, Bergljot, Dalla, Frijda, Gyda, Katla, Luta, Mina, Oline, Rita, Sigrun Tanja, Ygritte, Yrsa</p>
			<h4>AUSTRI TRAITS</h4>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Ability Score Increase </strong> Your Charisma score increases by 2 and your Wisdom score increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Age </strong> Austri live nearly 70-90 years and they become adults when they are 19.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Alignment </strong> They can be anything, most of the Austri tend to be lawful.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Size </strong> The Austri average is in between 5-7 feet and 125-250 pounds. </p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Speed </strong> Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Languages </strong> Austris (Common).</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Quick Thinking </strong> You have a +1 bonus on initiative rolls.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Kingdom’s Arsenal</strong> Due to conscription you are proficient with shortsword, longsword or warhammer.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Civilised</strong> You know how things work in a civilized society. You have advantage on your Charisma (Deception) or Charisma (Persuasion) checks.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="names" type="male">Asmund, Bergvid, Eiwald, Grimwald, Hamund, Iarl, Jarlebanke, Kolbein, Modolf, Odinqar, Othraq, Ragi, Thorwald, Ulfjolt, Varsvir</set>
			<set name="names" type="female">Astrid, Bergljot, Dalla, Frijda, Gyda, Katla, Luta, Mina, Oline, Rita, Sigrun Tanja, Ygritte, Yrsa</set>
			<set name="names format">{{name}}</set>
			<set name="height" modifier="2d8">6'0"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="2d6">180 lb.</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="charisma" value="2" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
			<stat name="wisdom" value="1" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Custom Ability Score Improvement +2 (Austri)" supports="Custom Ability Score Increase 2" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Custom Ability Score Improvement +1 (Austri)" supports="Custom Ability Score Increase 1" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />
			<select type="Language" name="Customized Language" supports="Custom Race Language" number="1"  requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="Quick Thinking" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="Kingdom’s Arsenal"/>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="Civilised"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Quick Thinking" type="Racial Trait" source="Svilland" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_QUICK_THINKING">
		<description>
			<p>You have a +1 bonus on initiative rolls.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have a +1 bonus on initiative rolls.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="initiative" value="1"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Kingdom’s Arsenal" type="Racial Trait" source="Svilland" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KINGDOMS_ARSENAL">
		<description>
			<p>Due to conscription you are proficient with shortsword, longsword or warhammer.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Due to conscription you are proficient with shortsword, longsword and warhammer.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGSWORD" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_WARHAMMER" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Simple/Martial Weapon or Tool, Kingdom’s Arsenal" number="2" supports="Weapon||Tool" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Civilised" type="Racial Trait" source="Svilland" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_CIVILISED">
		<description>
			<p>You know how things work in a civilized society. You have advantage on your Charisma (Deception) or Charisma (Persuasion) checks.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You know how things work in a civilized society. You have advantage on your Charisma (Deception) or Charisma (Persuasion) checks.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>